<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sheree Armistead</title>
    <link>https://shereearmistead.github.io/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://shereearmistead.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Sheree Armistead</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://shereearmistead.github.io/images/icon_hu07c7f6abe5f40b880a2343300b756d07_15024_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Sheree Armistead</title>
      <link>https://shereearmistead.github.io/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Preprint - PbIso: an R package and web app for calculating and plotting Pb isotope data</title>
      <link>https://shereearmistead.github.io/post/pbisoapppreprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shereearmistead.github.io/post/pbisoapppreprint/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This manuscript outlines a new R package and shiny web app for calculating and plotting Pb isotope data. Check out the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://eartharxiv.org/repository/view/2841/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EarthArXiv Preprint here&lt;/a&gt; and the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://shereearmistead.shinyapps.io/PbIsoApp/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;shiny web app here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt;
The package PbIso is a free and open R toolbox for commonly used calculations and plots of Pb-Pb isotope data. In this paper, we review Pb isotope systematics and the calculations that are commonly used, such as model age, model source 𝜇 (238U/204Pb), time-integrated 𝜅 (232Th/238U), and initial Pb isotope ratios. These complicated equations are implemented into simple R functions in the package PbIso. In addition, functions are provided for generating model curves, geochron lines, and time-dependent slopes. This allows users to apply calculations to their data in a straightforward way, while providing transparency and flexibility of the calculations used. We have implemented some basic features of the PbIso package into an online shiny application (&lt;a href=&#34;https://shereearmistead.shinyapps.io/PbIsoApp/),&#34;&gt;https://shereearmistead.shinyapps.io/PbIsoApp/),&lt;/a&gt;
which makes it easy for users without any R experience to use these calculations with their own data and to generate plots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Citation:&lt;/strong&gt;
Armistead, S.E., Eglington, B.M. and Pehrsson, S.J., 2021. “PbIso: an R package and web app for calculating and plotting Pb isotope data.” EarthArXiv. Nov 10. doi:10.31223/X56G84&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Preprint - Age and geochemistry of the Boucaut Volcanics</title>
      <link>https://shereearmistead.github.io/post/boucautpreprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shereearmistead.github.io/post/boucautpreprint/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This work provides important age constraints on stratigraphy in the Adelaide Rift Complex within the Adelaide Superbasin. Check out the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://eartharxiv.org/mgpf4/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EarthArXiv Preprint here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt;
The Adelaide Rift Complex in South Australia records the break-up of Rodinia at a time of great climatic and biological evolution. The Boucaut Volcanics within the Neoproterozoic Adelaide Rift Complex lie at the base of the Burra Group, marking the boundary between the Burra Group and underlying Callanna Group. Despite their significance as one of the few volcanic units within the rift complex, there has been no robust age determination published for the Boucaut Volcanics. We use U–Pb zircon LA-ICP-MS data to determine an age of 788 ± 6 Ma for the eruption of the bimodal Boucaut Volcanics. This has important implications for constraining the timing of stratigraphy within the Adelaide Rift Complex. This also has far reaching implications for plate tectonic reconstructions of Australia and Laurentia, and for correlating global isotope anomalies for the Neoproterozoic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Citation:&lt;/strong&gt;
Armistead, Sheree E., Alan Collins, Solomon Buckman, and Rachel Atkins. 2020. “Age and Geochemistry of the Boucaut Volcanics in the Neoproterozoic Adelaide Rift Complex, South Australia.” EarthArXiv. July 15. doi:10.31223/osf.io/mgpf4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img style=&#34;float: centre;&#34; src=&#34;https://shereearmistead.github.io/img/Boucaut.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;drawing&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Figure 1: GPlates tectonic reconstructions of the different Australia-Laurentia models at 788 Ma (the crystallisation age of the Boucaut Volcanics), made using the models in Merdith et al. (2017b). South Australia is fixed in its present-day position with all other blocks rotated relative to it at 788 Ma. SWEAT reconstruction based on Dalziel (1991);Hoffman (1991); Moores (1991). AUSWUS reconstruction based on Karlstrom et al. (1999). AUSMEX reconstruction based on Wingate et al. (2002). Missing Link reconstruction based on Li et al. (1995). NA = North Australia, SA = South Australia.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Seminar Series - IGCP 648 Supercontinent Cycles and Global Geodynamics</title>
      <link>https://shereearmistead.github.io/post/igcp648post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shereearmistead.github.io/post/igcp648post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The IGCP 648 (Supercontinent Cycles and Global Geodynamics) is a collaborative project involving researchers from all around the world. I&amp;rsquo;ve been fortunate to be involved in the IGCP 648 group over the past few years and they have supported me to attend conferences and field symposia. In response to the global COVID-19 crisis and the reduced connectivity among colleagues, I have organised a weekly Virtual Seminar Series hosted on zoom for the tectonics/geodynamics community. We hear from a diverse range of scientists researching many aspects relating to plate tectonics and geodynamics. Importantly, we are able to share science with a whole range of people from different parts of the world, many of who would not normally be able to attend in person conferences and seminars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://geodynamics.curtin.edu.au/igcp-648-virtual-seminar-series&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;IGCP 648 Virtual Seminar Series website&lt;/a&gt; for more information and to see past seminar recordings:&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
